Finding Aid for Detroit News Lansing Bureau scrapbooks, 1931-1972
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Detroit News Lansing Bureau scrapbooks
1931-1972
Detroit News Lansing Bureau.
851119 Bb.1 2
Newspaper clippings detailing all aspects of state government, including the gubernatorial administrations of Kim Sigler, G. Mennen Williams, John B. Swainson, and George Romney; also; and miscellaneous reference files, including political and governmental press releases.
30 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The scrapbooks were donated by the Detroit News Lansing Bureau (donor no. 5543 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Detroit News Lansing Bureau was responsible for reporting news of Michigan government and politics, including the activities of the governor and the workings of the legislature.
The records consists primarily of scrapbooks dating from 1931 to 1966, miscellaneous press and reference files, and clippings of articles by reporter Glenn Engle. The scrapbooks provide detailed and complete coverage of state government with particular emphasis on the gubernatorial administrations of Kim Sigler, G. Mennen Williams, John Swainson and George Romney. There are also clippings pertaining to Michigan politics, the work of Michigan's Grand Jury (1943-1962), and the state constitutional convention, 1961-1964.
Subjects:
Michigan. Constitutional Convention (1961-1962); Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Michigan--Politics and government--1939-1945.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Romney, George W., 1907-1995.; Sigler, Kim, b. 1894.; Swainson, John B. (John Burley), 1925-1994.; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
Contributors:
Engle, Glenn.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- Scrapbooks
  - January-May 1931, December 1932-December 1935 (Box 1)
  - December 1935-April 1938 (Box 2)
  - April 1938-January 1940 (Box 3)
  - January 1940-October 1941 (Box 4)
  - October 1941-September 1943 (Box 5)
  - September 1943-November 1945 (Box 6)
  - November 1945-April 1947 (Box 7)
  - April 1947-December 1948 (Box 8)
  - December 1948-January 1951 (Box 9)
  - January 1951-June 1952 (Box 10)
  - June 1952-July 1953 (Box 11)
  - July 1953-December 1954 (Box 12)
  - December 1954-September 1956 (Box 13)
  - September 1956-November 1958 (Box 14)
  - November 1958-May 1960 (Box 15)
  - May 1960-January 1962 (Box 16)
  - January 1962-March 1963 (Box 17)
  - March 1963-August 1964 (Box 18)
  - August 1964-March 1966 (Box 19)
  - March 1966-December 1966 (Box 20)
  - Concerning gubernatorial administration of Kim Sigler, 1946-1947 (Box 20)
  - Concerning gubernatorial administration of G. Mennen Williams, 1947-February 1955 (Box 21)
  - Concerning gubernatorial administration and African career of G. Mennen Williams, February 1955-September 1963 (Box 22)
  - Concerning gubernatorial administration of John B. Swainson, November 1960-September 1963 (Box 23)
  - Concerning gubernatorial administration of George Romney, May 1962-October 1965 (Box 23)
  - Concerning Michigan politics, May 1945-December 1966 (Box 23)
  - Concerning Michigan's Grand Jury, November 1943-August 1956 (Box 24)
  - Concerning Michigan's Grand Jury, August 1956-1962 (Box 25)
  - "The Constitutional Convention", June 1961-April 1964 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 25)
- Press and reference files
  - Michigan Joint Legislative Committee on Reorganization of State Government (Box 26)
  - Constitutional Convention (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 28)
    (continued)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 29)
  - Clippings of articles by Glenn Engle, 1956-1972 (Box 30)